Teiko Middle School
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Aomine Daiki.
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
This is mine.
（灰崎(はいざき)）こいつはオレのもんだ
（黄瀬(きせ)）あっ！
That shot is mine!
（灰崎）もらったぜ
さっきの
Like Kise-kun, Haizaki-kun makes moves
his own after seeing them only once.
（黒子(くろこ)）灰崎君は黄瀬君同様—
見た技を一瞬で自分のものにする
That's mine.
もーらいっ
（黒子）ですがリズムやテンポだけ
我流に変えてしまうんです
However, he uses his own rhythm and tempo.
（森山(もりやま)）あれ？
What?
Haizaki-kun doesn't copy moves.
（黒子）コピーではなく
灰崎君は技を奪う
He steals them.
〝キセキの世代〞？
The Generation of Miracles?
Don't make me laugh.
笑わせんなよ
この程度でよく言うぜ
That's some big talk when
this is all you can do.
Stay Out of My Way
（灰崎）ふーん… いいじゃん
That's pretty nice.
（高校生１）はー
なあ それ放ってくんねー？
Hey, toss us the ball!
Who is he?
（高校生２）何 あいつ？
見たとこ中坊だけど
He looks like a middle schooler.
（高校生３）おっ
Isn't that Teiko's uniform?
あの制服…
帝光のヤツじゃね？
That place with the unusually
strong basketball team?
（高校生２）あのバスケ部が
異様に 強(つえ)えとかっていうトコ？
Really?
（高校生１）へー
おいクソガキ　ちょっと来い
オレらが遊んでやんよ
Hey, shithead. Come here.
We'll play with you.
（高校生１）あっ！
（高校生２）うあっ！
（灰崎）へ… へへ… ふんっ！
（高校生３）く… くそっ！
Damn it!
（高校生２）何なんだ こいつ
Who is this guy?
I thought your moves were pretty nice,
but they weren't worth stealing.
オマエの技はちょっと
いいかと思ったけど—
奪うほどのモンでもなかったわ
You guys are nothing.
てかあんたら チョロすぎ
You should be grateful I was
willing to play with you.
遊んでもらえただけ
感謝しろよ
（高校生１）
オ… オマエ まさか…
A-Are you
one of the Generation of Miracles?
あの“キセキの世代”なのか？
（灰崎）チッ
また“キセキの世代”かよ
The Generation of Miracles again?
オレが辞めてから—
Since I quit, every time someone mentions
Teiko, everyone always brings them up.
帝光って言やあ
どいつもこいつも…
That's fine, I guess.
ま そんならそんで いいや
I'll just steal it if I want it.
欲しくなったら 奪うだけだ
Bring me a drink!
おい ドリンク！
Make it snappy, idiots!
タラタラしてんじゃねえよ
バーカ！
Since Haizaki joined, the team has changed.
（石田(いしだ)）灰崎…
コイツが入って
チームは変わってしまった
だが それでも強い！
But he's still strong.
“キセキの世代”
黄瀬涼太を圧倒し—
Strong enough to crush Kise Ryota
of the Generation of Miracles
and corner the mighty Kaijo.
強豪海常(かいじょう)を追い詰めるほどに
Physically he's Kise's equal, and he
can steal his opponents' techniques...
（武内(たけうち)）黄瀬と遜色ない
身体能力に—
技を奪うというスタイル…
想像以上に厄介な相手だ
He's more of a problem than we expected.
Kasamatsu's moving the ball around,
and Kise's doing his best,
（森山）笠松(かさまつ)から
うまくボールを回して—
黄瀬が頑張ってくれてはいるが
Kaijo
Fukuda Sogo
but as the game drags on, we lose
more abilities and offensive strength!
試合が進むほど—
技を奪われて
攻撃力が下がる一方だ！
（笠松）どうする？
What should we do?
At this rate, we'll be in serious trouble!
このままじゃマジでヤベエ…
くうっ…
Another one-handed dunk.
（火神(かがみ)）またワンハンドダンク
But that rhythm...
（火神）けどそのリズムじゃ…
He's way worse than usual!
（笠松）いつものキレが
全然出せてねえ！
I just took that during the second quarter.
（灰崎）それはさっき
第２クオーターでもらったろうが
It's not yours anymore.
もうオマエのもんじゃねえ
It's mine.
オレのもんだ
Captain!
（望月(もちづき)）キャプテン！
Give it to me!
（灰崎）よこせ！
（望月）うっ！
Damn it!
くそっ！
I'll show you how to do it.
手本を見せてやんよ
You do it like this!
こーだよっ！
Fukuda Sogo's in complete
control of the game.
（伊月(いづき)）流れは完全に福田(ふくだ)総合…
（日向(ひゅうが)）灰崎ってヤツ
まさかこれほどとは…
I had no idea Haizaki was so strong.
（小堀(こぼり)）う…
（早川(はやかわ)）あ… あいえねぇ！
Impossible!
He's copying him perfectly.
ここまで完璧に…
Something's wrong with Kise's movements.
（火神）黄瀬の動きがおかしい…
He's not his usual self.
いつものあいつじゃねえ
はい
You're right.
Though his moves have been stolen,
I can't imagine Kise-kun falling this hard.
技を奪われたとはいえ—
黄瀬君がここまで
崩れるとは思えません
This isn't good.
（青峰(あおみね)）ヤベエな
（さつき）え？
What?
Kise learns moves after seeing them once.
一度見れば
技を習得できる黄瀬は—
He should have a pretty significant
number of moves stored up.
これまでに相当の量のストックを
溜めてるはずだ
But not many of them will
work against Haizaki.
だがその中で灰崎に
通用するものとなれば—
そう多くはねえ
On top of that, they'll be stolen as soon
as he uses them, making them useless.
しかも使った先から奪われ
使用不能になっていく
He's been carefully choosing
from a limited set of choices,
限られた中から慎重に選んで
戦ってきたが—
but he's starting to run out of options.
いよいよストックが尽き始めたな
そんなっ！
But...
And that's not the only problem,
（青峰）しかも
問題はそれだけじゃねえだろ
is it, Kise?
黄瀬！
黄瀬！ 飛ばしすぎだ
少しセーブしろ！
Kise!
You're going too hard! Save your strength!
It's not enough.
（黄瀬）まだまだなんス
（笠松）ああ？
What?
It's not enough.
I can't get there like this...
これじゃ 届かない
（黄瀬）えいっ！
He's overworked?
（伊月）オーバーワーク？
Probably.
（リコ）たぶんね
I can't imagine Aomine-kun was the only one
（リコ）インターハイの
海常 対 桐皇(とうおう)戦
who injured himself during the
Inter-High's Kaijo-Touou game.
あの戦いで体を痛めたのが
青峰君だけとは思えないわ
Kise-kun has probably been practicing
hard without recovering completely.
恐らく黄瀬君も…
完治しないまま
ハードな練習を積んでしまったのよ
うっ！ そんな！
But...
Don't lose in the preliminaries!
（黄瀬）予選で負けんなよ！
Of course.
トーゼンっス！
それでも あいつが負けるわけねえ
But there's no way he'd
lose to that shithead.
あんなクソヤローに
He promised to win so we could
play in the semifinals.
約束したんだ
勝って次の準決勝でやるって
He won't lose!
だからあいつは絶対…
He made another shot!
（観客１）また決まった！
（観客２）すげえぞ あいつ
黄瀬を圧倒してる！
He's amazing! He's shutting out Kise!
（観客３）“キセキの世代”と
同格ってことかよ
Is he as good as the Generation of Miracles?
Impossible...
バカな…
黄瀬がまるで歯が立たない？
Kise doesn't stand a chance.
Kaijo
Fukuda Sogo
I'm starting to run out of moves.
（黄瀬）技のストックも
底をついてきたってのに
Damn it. And my foot...
くそっ… 足も…
Come to think of it, you used to grovel on
your knees in middle school, too, Ryota.
（灰崎）そういや
中坊んときも—
そうやって はいつくばってたな
涼太
そうだ そうだ
Oh, right.
しかも女もオレが
取っちまったんだっけ？
And I stole your girlfriend, didn't I?
That was pathetic.
みじめだな つくづく
I dumped her as soon as I
was done with her, though.
まあ ヤったら
すぐ捨てちまったけど！ アハハハ
That bastard's head is big enough!
あのヤー
どーかーでも調子ーやがって
聞くに堪えんな
It's unspeakable.
Hey, you!
（審判）ちょっと 君！
さっきから口がすぎるぞ
You've crossed the line!
That's enough!
これ以上は…
Yeah, yeah. I'll be careful.
はいはい
気をつけますって
Kise...
（笠松）黄瀬…
Ki-chan...
きーちゃん…
Are you
（火神）まさか…
ヤラレっぱなしで終わるってのかよ
going to take this lying down?
オマエが！
Kuroko?
黒子？
信じてますから！ 黄瀬君!!
I believe in you, Kise-kun!
（観客）すごい大きな声
したけど…
Kurokocchi...
黒子っち…
Shogo-kun, you know...
祥吾(しょうご)君さ
Before I beat you,
勝つ前に言っとくけど—
you should know you have
the wrong idea about her.
カン違いしてるよ
あの子のこととか
What?
The way she followed me around and called
herself my girlfriend was annoying.
（黄瀬）勝手につきまとって
彼女名乗られて—
うんざりしてたんスよ 正直
She was totally arrogant and always
bragged about herself.
プライド高くて自慢話ばっか
She just wanted people to
know she was dating a model.
モデルと付き合ってるって—
ステータスが欲しかっただけ
なんスよ あれは
All you did was take one of the stupid women
who flocked to me because of my appearance.
見た目で群がってくるバカ女たちの
１人取ったくらいで—
Don't let it get to your head.
調子に乗ってんじゃねえよ
What?
黄瀬！
Kise!
戻れ！
Go back!
You have nothing left!
テメーにゃ もうなんもねえ
残りカスなんだよ 涼太！
You're just dregs now, Ryota!
Who?
誰が？
Doesn't that mean we can be friends now?
じゃ これなら
仲良くできるんじゃないスか？
Our styles are completely different!
スタイルが全然違う！
What...
（灰崎）なっ!?
（一同）ぬあっ！
What?
Is that...
（石田）まさか あれは…
...the Generation of Miracle's Midorima
Shintaro's high trajectory three-pointer?
（石田）“キセキの世代”
緑間真太郎の—
高弾道スリー
“キセキの世代”のコピーだけは
できなかったはずじゃ！
I thought he couldn't copy the other
members of the Generation of Miracles!
He overcame that,
（笠松）克服したのさ
but using their abilities
takes a major toll on his body.
だが“キセキの世代”の技は—
体への負担が大きく 制限がある
At most he can do it for five
minutes. But right now, Kise can
いいとこ５分
けど 今の黄瀬は—
use all the abilities
of the Generation of Miracles.
“キセキの世代”の技
すべてが使える—
It is a flawless imitation.
完全無欠の模倣
パーフェクトコピー！
A Perfect Copy!
If it's women or titles you
want, you can have them all.
（黄瀬）女だの肩書きだの—
欲しけりゃくれてやるよ
いくらでも
I have a more important promise to keep.
んなことより大事な約束が
あるんスよ オレには
I will make it there.
必ずそこへ行く
ジャマすんじゃねーよ！
Stay out of my way!
Piece of shit!
（灰崎）クソが！
It's no use!
ダメだ
あいつらの技だけは
Not even I
can steal their abilities!
オレにも奪えねえ
ええい！
（観客１）うおお 黄瀬がすげえ
すごすぎる！
Kise's amazing! He's unbelievable!
（観客２）海常猛追だー！
Kaijo's catching up!
All right!
（小堀）よし！
We're seven points down!
（笠松）７点差
一気に畳みかけっぞ！
Let's close that gap!
Don't be ridiculous, shitheads...
（灰崎）ざけんな
Kaijo
Fukuda Sogo
クソが
ぬあああああ！ でいっ！
（福田総合５番）
スクープショット！
A scoop shot!
Haizaki, what was that?
灰崎 それは!?
The idiot is shaken.
（青峰）バカが 動揺しやがって
Why are you stealing your
teammates' abilities?
味方の技 奪ってどうする
（黄瀬）いやああっ
His reactions and intensity rival Atsushi's!
（灰崎）敦と遜色ねえ反応と迫力
Even his blocks...
ブロックまで!?
He can even copy Murasakibara?
紫原のコピーまで？
In his game against Touou, Kise-kun
インターハイの対桐皇戦で
黄瀬君は最低速を下げて—
recreated the rapid speed change
of Aomine-kun's changeover
青峰君と同じ速度差の
チェンジオブペースを再現したわ
by dropping his minimum speed.
He also achieved the range
of Midorima-kun's shot
同時に
緑間君のシュートは—
by holding the shot with his dominant hand,
利き腕で より溜めて打つことで
飛距離を
and he's reproducing Murasakibara's defense
with his jumping ability and predictions.
紫原君のディフェンスは
ジャンプ力と予測で—
守備範囲を再現している
But the abilities of the Generation of
Miracles aren't reproduced that easily.
けど それだけでできるほど—
“キセキの世代”の技術は
易しくない
Kise Ryota's basketball sense is bottomless.
黄瀬涼太
底なしのバスケセンスだ
Bastard...
テメー…
Shogo-kun, you said you'd steal the title
of the Generation of Miracles, right?
祥吾君
さっき言ってたっスね
〝キセキの世代の
座を—〞
〝奪っちまおうと思って〞
だっけ？
How do you feel now?
（黄瀬）調子は どうっスか？
It's a comeback!
（観客）逆転！
海常が逆転だー！
Kaijo's making a comeback!
What? Akashi, what did you just say?
（灰崎）ああ!?
赤司テメー 今 何つった？
Quit the basketball team. That's an order.
（赤司）バスケ部を辞めろ
これは命令だ
What?
ンだと！
I'm actually being considerate of you.
（赤司）むしろ これは
オマエを気づかってのことだ
100 Battles 100 Victories
Teiko Middle School Basketball Team
素行は決して
褒められたものではないが—
Though your behavior is hardly praiseworthy,
今まで帝光の勝利に貢献してきた
you have contributed to
Teiko's victories until now.
However, you cannot beat Kise.
だがオマエは
黄瀬には勝てない
In the near future, he will
replace you as a starter.
近い将来 スタメンの座を
奪われるだろう
You are too proud to stick around.
そうなれば—
プライドの高いオマエは
結局いなくなる
He'll replace me?
このオレが奪われるだと？
It'll happen sooner or later.
早いか遅いかだ
どちらにせよ
結果は変わらない
But either way, the result will be the same.
You bastard...
（灰崎）テメー
Was Akashi right?
（灰崎）赤司の
言うとおりだったってのかよ
I have to admit, though...
けど…
認めるしかねえな
Ryota, you're strong.
涼太 テメーは強い
I don't care what happens now.
ならもう
どうなろうが知んねえよ
（灰崎）ぶっ潰してやる！
I'll destroy you!
（灰崎）えいっ！
（灰崎）気づいてねえとでも
思ったのかよ？
Did you think I didn't notice
your foot was injured?
テメーが足を痛めてるってよ！
（黒子）う！
（火神）今 足を!?
His foot...
It happened so quickly,
the referee didn't notice!
（笠松）一瞬のことで
審判も気づいてねえ！
ええい！ 終わりだ！
This is the end!
I thought I told you
（黄瀬）言ったはずっスよ
to stay out of my way!
ジャマすんじゃねーって!!
勝つのはオマエじゃない！
オレだ！
You won't win!
I will!
黄瀬ー！
Kise!
（森山）黄瀬！
（早川）行けー！ 黄瀬！
Kise!
Go, Kise!
（黄瀬）だああっ！
Kaijo
Fukuda Sogo
The game's over!
（観客）試合終了だー！
Yes!
（早川）しゃあああ！
Kise!
（小堀）黄瀬！
（笠松）やったな！
We did it!
（黄瀬）痛っ… 痛い 痛いっス
バカになるっス…
Ow!
You're killing my brain cells!
Our next opponent...
（木吉）次の相手は…
...is Kaijo.
（日向）海常！
ハァ… フゥー
You guys were a terrifying team that
didn't give up until the very end.
（笠松）最後まで諦めねえ
おっかないチームだったぜ
Win for us, too.
勝てよ オレたちの分も
You were strong.
強かったぜ オマエら
You go on ahead, Satsuki.
先帰ってろ さつき
Huh?
ちょっ 大ちゃん!?
Hey, Dai-chan!
（青峰）海常なら
まだ出てこねえぜ
Kaijo's not coming out yet.
If you're thinking about getting
revenge on Kise, don't bother.
黄瀬に復讐しようとか
考えてんなら やめとけ
Daiki.
大輝…
If you'll go home quietly, I'll let this go.
今 おとなしく帰れば見逃してやる
Whatever, idiot.
知るかバーカ
何しようがオレの勝手だろうが
I'll do what I want.
If you're going to play ball,
I don't care what you do.
バスケだったら
何しようが文句はねえよ
けどな—
But don't mess with them by
doing stupid shit off the court.
それ以外の
くだらねえ やり方で—
あいつらの戦いに
チャチャ入れんじゃねえよ
ふっ… っかしーな
That's odd.
Have you always been such a good little boy?
オマエ そんなに
いい子ちゃんだったか？
You lost to Kise, Haizaki.
（青峰）テメエは黄瀬に
負けたんだよ 灰崎
あいつやテツが
今までどんだけ鍛えてきたか
You have no idea how much
he and Tetsu have trained.
これ以上バカげたマネすんな
Don't do anything else stupid.
I see.
（灰崎）そうか
Now I really have to destroy them.
じゃあ なおさら
ぶっ潰してやんねえとな
I told you, I don't care.
（灰崎）知るかっつってんだろ
Unfortunately, unlike you guys,
I don't give a shit about basketball.
あいにくオレはオマエらと違って
バスケを何とも思ってねえ
If you want me to stop,
やめて欲しけりゃ—
make me!
力ずくでやってみろよ!!
ぐわっ！
Then I will.
（青峰）じゃあ
そうさせてもらうわ
（青峰）さて
どーすっかな この後…
What should I do now?
I'm sure it'll work out.
ま なるように なんだろう
You don't care as long
as it's basketball, huh?
“バスケだったら
文句はねえ”だと？
（黒子）灰崎君
Haizaki-kun!
Huh?
Tetsuya.
テツヤじゃねえか
Is it true you're quitting
the basketball team?
バスケ部辞めるって本当ですか？
Yeah. So what?
あー そうだけど？
そんなすごい才能があるのに
なんで？
But you have such amazing talent. Why?
ハハッ！
てかオマエ 何しに来たんだ？
Why did you even come here? Are you stupid?
バカか？
It's not like we're friends.
別にオレと仲良くも
なんもなかったろうが
そういう問題じゃありません
That's not the issue.
チッ っせーな
Shut up.
I'm tired of basketball.
バスケに飽きた
そんだけだ バーカ
That's all, idiot.
It's tiring and makes me stink.
疲れるし 汗くせえし
女と遊んでるほうが
よっぽど楽しいぜ
I have way more fun hanging out with girls.
Is that how you really feel, Haizaki-kun?
（黒子）それは
灰崎君の本心ですか？
You really are an idiot.
（灰崎）ホントバカだな オマエ
（黒子）あ…
Do you think deep down I'm actually serious?
実はオレが
根がマジメだとでも思ってんのか？
Some guys really are bad to
the bone, or even terrifying.
（灰崎）本当に悪いヤツや—
怖(こえ)えヤツだっているんだぜ
Later.
じゃあな
You'd better not pity me or anything.
同情なんてズレたこと
思ってんじゃねえよ
There's no guarantee the rest of you who
stay on the team won't be worse off.
残ったオマエらのほうが—
かわいそうな目に遭わねえとは
限らねえんだぜ
（灰崎）そうだ
That's right.
It's worse for the guys who stayed.
残ったヤツらのほうがな
What's wrong, Kuroko?
（火神）どうした 黒子？
Nothing.
（黒子）いえ 何でもありません
And so, the curtains closed on
the fifth day of the Winter Cup.
（リコ）こうしてウインターカップ
５日目は幕を閉じた
Seirin
Shutoku
Kaijo
Rakuzan
Only...
そして ついに—
...the four semifinalists remained.
４強が出そろった
Preview
Satsuki!
（青峰）さつき！ いきなり
人んち来て 何あさってんだよ
You can't just show up at someone's house
and start digging through their stuff!
Dai-chan, you have the same shoes as
Kagamin but in a different color, right?
（さつき）大ちゃん
かがみんと同じバッシュ—
色違いで持ってたよね？
（青峰）あ？ 火神？
バッシュ？
What? Kagamin? Shoes?
I'll Take It
（さつき）あ！ あった！
Here they are!
（青峰）おい！ 勝手に出すなよ
Hey, don't take those out!
Hey, Satsuki!
おい！ さつき！